A Guide to the Southern Student Organizing Committee Papers 1964-1968
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Southern Student Organizing Committee Papers 1964-1968
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11192
This collection consists of 110 items.
This collection consists of the papers of the Southern Student Organizing Committee, 1964-1968, "an association of young, concerned Southerners dedicated to social change" formed in the spring of 1964.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Archie E. Allen, Santa Barbara, California, on July 13, 1995, with no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the papers of the Southern Student Organizing Committee, 1964-1968, "an association of young, concerned Southerners dedicated to social change" formed in the spring of 1964. The papers include correspondence, memoranda, newsclippings, reports, typescripts, and printed material. Correspondents include Archie E. Allen (Field Secretary, SSOC & Kentucky Commission on Human Rights); Jacob Clayman; Deborah M. Cole (Executive Secretary, The Aaron E. Norman Fund, Inc.); Leon J. Davis (President Local 1199); Todd Gitlin (President of Students for a Democratic Society); Maxwell Hahn (Executive Vice President, The Field Foundation); Ed Hamlett; Philip J. Hirschkop; Joel R. Jacobson (President of New Jersy State Industrial Union Council AFL-CIO); Deirdre La Pin (Georgia Students for Human Rights); Howard Romaine; Benjamin Spaulding; and Sue Thrasher (Executive Secretary, SSOC).
Contents List
- By-Laws, Organization & History ca. 1964-1967
- Conferences & Meetings 1964-1966
  Meetings held at Old Gammon Seminary Campus, Atlanta, Georgia; The Buckeye Cove Conference, North Carolina; and the Students and Labor Conference, Durham, North Carolina
- Correspondence 1964-1966
- News clippings, Printed & Press Releases 1964-1967
- Officers, Committees & Contact Persons 1964, n.d.
- Projects 1966, n.d.
  Including community projects, the National Student Association Project, and the Tennessee Spring Project
- Prospectuses n.d.
- Publications 1967, n.d.
  Including "Nashville: A Preliminary Study of the Power Structure" by Dave & Ronda Kotelchuck; "The New Nonviolence" by Dave Dellinger; "Toward a Female Liberation Movement" by Beverly Jones and Judith Brown; "Vietnam: Myth and Reality of American Policy" by David Nolan
- "The Southern Student Organizing Committee" by Ron K. Parker 1965 Jan 5, A class paper
- "Speakers Guide" compiled by Lyn Wells 1968